<fields date="2019-03-03">
<field name="ab" gloss="anonymous block">contains any arbitrary component-level unit of text, acting as an anonymous container for phrase or inter level elements analogous to, but without the semantic baggage of, a paragraph.</field>
<field name="abbr" gloss="abbreviation">contains an abbreviation of any sort.</field>
<field name="abstract" gloss="">contains a summary or formal abstract prefixed to an existing source document by the encoder.</field>
<field name="accMat" gloss="accompanying material">contains details of any significant additional material which may be closely associated with the manuscript or object being described, such as non-contemporaneous documents or fragments bound in with it at some earlier historical period.</field>
<field name="acquisition" gloss="">contains any descriptive or other information concerning the process by which a manuscript or manuscript part or other object entered the holding institution.</field>
<field name="activity" gloss="">contains a brief informal description of what a participant in a language interaction is doing other than speaking, if anything.</field>
<field name="actor" gloss="">contains the name of an actor appearing within a cast list.</field>
<field name="add" gloss="addition">contains letters, words, or phrases inserted in the source text by an author, scribe, or a previous annotator or corrector.</field>
<field name="additional" gloss="">groups additional information, combining bibliographic information about a manuscript or other object, or surrogate copies of it, with curatorial or administrative information.</field>
<field name="additions" gloss="">contains a description of any significant additions found within a manuscript or other object, such as marginalia or other annotations.</field>
<field name="addName" gloss="additional name">contains an additional name component, such as a nickname, epithet, or alias, or any other descriptive phrase used within a personal name.</field>
<field name="address" gloss="">contains a postal address, for example of a publisher, an organization, or an individual.</field>
<field name="addrLine" gloss="address line">contains one line of a postal<!-- or other--> address.</field>
<field name="addSpan" gloss="added span of text">marks the beginning of a longer sequence of text added by an author, scribe, annotator or corrector (see also <gi>add</gi>).</field>
<field name="adminInfo" gloss="administrative information">contains information about the present custody and availability of the manuscript or other object, and also about the record description itself.</field>
<field name="affiliation" gloss="">contains an informal description of a person's present or past affiliation with some organization, for example an employer or sponsor.</field>
<field name="age" gloss="in world">specifies the age of a person.</field>
<field name="alt" gloss="alternation">identifies an alternation or a set of choices among elements or passages.</field>
<field name="alternate" gloss="">indicates that the constructs referenced by its children form an alternation</field>
<field name="altGrp" gloss="alternation group">groups a collection of <gi>alt</gi> elements and possibly pointers.</field>
<field name="altIdent" gloss="alternate identifier">supplies the recommended XML name for an element, class, attribute, etc. in some language.</field>
<field name="altIdentifier" gloss="alternative identifier">contains an alternative or former structured identifier used for a manuscript or other object, such as a former catalogue number.</field>
<field name="am" gloss="abbreviation marker">contains a sequence of letters or signs present in an abbreviation which are omitted or replaced in the expanded form of the abbreviation.</field>
<field name="analytic" gloss="analytic level">contains bibliographic elements describing an item (e.g. an article or poem) published within a monograph or journal and not as an independent publication.</field>
<field name="anchor" gloss="anchor point">attaches an identifier to a point within a text, whether or not it corresponds with a textual element.</field>
<field name="annotationBlock" gloss="">groups together various annotations, e.g. for parallel interpretations of a spoken segment.</field>
<field name="anyElement" gloss="">indicates the presence of any elements in a content model</field>
<field name="app" gloss="apparatus entry">contains one entry in a critical apparatus, with an optional lemma and usually one or more readings or notes on the relevant passage.</field>
<field name="appInfo" gloss="application information">records information about an application which has edited the TEI file.</field>
<field name="application" gloss="">provides information about an application which has acted upon the document.</field>
<field name="arc" gloss="">encodes an arc, the connection from one node to another in a graph.</field>
<field name="argument" gloss="">contains a formal list or prose description of the topics addressed by 	a subdivision of a text.</field>
<field name="att.ascribed.directed" gloss="">provides attributes for elements representing speech or action that can be directed at a group or individual.</field>
<field name="att.ascribed" gloss="">provides attributes for elements representing speech or action that can be ascribed to a specific individual.</field>
<field name="att.breaking" gloss="">provides an attribute to indicate whether or not the element concerned is considered to mark the end of an orthographic token in the same way as whitespace.</field>
<field name="att.canonical" gloss="reference">provides attributes which can be used to associate a representation such as a name or title with canonical information about the object being named or referenced.</field>
<field name="att.citing" gloss="">provides attributes for specifying the specific part of a bibliographic item being cited.</field>
<field name="att.combinable" gloss="">provides attributes indicating how multiple references to the same object in a schema should be combined</field>
<field name="att.coordinated" gloss="">provides attributes which can be used to position their parent element within a two dimensional coordinate system.</field>
<field name="att.cReferencing" gloss="canonical reference">provides an attribute which may be used to supply a <term>canonical reference</term> as a means of identifying the target of a pointer.</field>
<field name="att.damaged" gloss="">provides attributes describing the nature of any physical damage affecting a reading.</field>
<field name="att.datable.custom" gloss="">provides attributes for normalization of elements that contain datable events to a custom dating system (i.e. other than the Gregorian used by W3 and ISO).</field>
<field name="att.datable.iso" gloss="">provides attributes for normalization of elements that contain datable events using the ISO 8601 standard.</field>
<field name="att.datable.w3c" gloss="">provides attributes for normalization of elements that contain datable events conforming to the W3C <title ref="#XSD2">XML Schema Part 2: Datatypes Second Edition</title>.</field>
<field name="att.datable" gloss="">provides attributes for normalization of elements that contain dates, times, or datable events.</field>
<field name="att.datcat" gloss="">provides the <att>dcr:datacat</att> and <att>dcr:ValueDatacat</att> attributes which are used to align XML elements or attributes with the appropriate Data Categories (DCs) defined by the ISO 12620:2009 standard and stored in the Web repository called ISOCat at <ref target="http://www.isocat.org/">http://www.isocat.org/</ref>.</field>
<field name="att.declarable" gloss="">provides attributes for those elements in the TEI header which may be independently selected by means of the special purpose <att>decls</att> attribute.</field>
<field name="att.declaring" gloss="">provides attributes for elements which may be independently associated with a particular declarable element within the header, thus overriding the inherited default for that element.</field>
<field name="att.deprecated" gloss="">provides attributes indicating how a deprecated feature will be treated in future releases.</field>
<field name="att.dimensions" gloss="centimetres">provides attributes for describing the size of physical objects.</field>
<field name="att.divLike" gloss="organization">provides attributes common to all elements which behave in the same way as divisions.</field>
<field name="att.docStatus" gloss="">provides attributes for use on metadata elements describing the status of a document.</field>
<field name="att.duration.iso" gloss="duration">provides attributes for recording normalized temporal durations.</field>
<field name="att.duration.w3c" gloss="duration">provides attributes for recording normalized temporal durations.</field>
<field name="att.duration" gloss="">provides attributes for normalization of elements that contain datable events.</field>
<field name="att.edition" gloss="edition">provides attributes identifying the source edition from which some encoded feature derives.</field>
<field name="att.editLike" gloss="">provides attributes describing the nature of an encoded scholarly intervention or interpretation of any kind.</field>
<field name="att.enjamb" gloss="enjambement">provides an attribute which may be used to indicate enjambement of the parent element.</field>
<field name="att.entryLike" gloss="homograph">provides an attribute used to distinguish different styles of dictionary entries.</field>
<field name="att.fragmentable" gloss="yes">provides an attribute for representing fragmentation of a structural element, typically as a consequence of some overlapping hierarchy.</field>
<field name="att.global.analytic" gloss="analysis">provides additional global attributes for associating specific analyses or interpretations with appropriate portions of a text.</field>
<field name="att.global.change" gloss="">supplies the <att>change</att> attribute, allowing its member elements to specify one or more states or revision campaigns with which they are associated.</field>
<field name="att.global.facs" gloss="facsimile">provides an attribute used to express correspondence between an element containing transcribed text and all or part of an image representing that text.</field>
<field name="att.global.linking" gloss="corresponds">provides a set of attributes for hypertextual linking.</field>
<field name="att.global.rendition" gloss="rendition">provides rendering attributes common to all elements in the TEI encoding scheme.</field>
<field name="att.global.responsibility" gloss="certainty">provides attributes indicating the agent responsible for some aspect of the text, the markup or something asserted by the markup, and the degree of certainty associated with it.</field>
<field name="att.global.source" gloss="">provides an attribute used by elements to point to an external source.</field>
<field name="att.global" gloss="identifier">provides attributes common to all elements in the TEI encoding scheme.</field>
<field name="att.handFeatures" gloss="">provides attributes describing aspects of the hand in which a manuscript is written.</field>
<field name="att.identified" gloss="">provides the identifying attribute for elements which can be subsequently referenced by means of a <att>key</att> attribute.</field>
<field name="att.internetMedia" gloss="MIME media type">provides attributes for specifying the type of a computer resource using a standard taxonomy.</field>
<field name="att.interpLike" gloss="instances">provides attributes for elements which represent a formal analysis or interpretation.</field>
<field name="att.lexicographic" gloss="normalized">provides a set of attributes for specifying standard and normalized values, grammatical functions, alternate or equivalent forms, and information about composite parts.</field>
<field name="att.linguistic" gloss="the token is not adjacent to another">provides a set of attributes concerning linguistic features of tokens, for usage within token-level elements, specifically <gi>w</gi> and <gi>pc</gi> in the analysis module.</field>
<field name="att.measurement" gloss="metre">provides attributes to represent a regularized or normalized measurement.</field>
<field name="att.media" gloss="">provides attributes for specifying display and related properties of external media.</field>
<field name="att.metrical" gloss="metrical structure, conventional">defines a set of attributes which certain elements may use to represent metrical information.</field>
<field name="att.milestoneUnit" gloss="">provides an attribute to indicate the type of section which is changing at a specific milestone.</field>
<field name="att.msClass" gloss="">provides an attribute to indicate text type or classification.</field>
<field name="att.msExcerpt" gloss="manuscript excerpt">provides attributes used to describe excerpts from a manuscript placed in a description thereof.</field>
<field name="att.namespaceable" gloss="namespace">provides an attribute indicating the target namespace for an object being created</field>
<field name="att.naming" gloss="reference to the canonical name">provides attributes common to elements which refer to named persons, places, organizations etc.</field>
<field name="att.notated" gloss="">provides an attribute to indicate any specialised notation used for element content.</field>
<field name="att.partials" gloss="full form">provides attributes for describing the extent of lexical references for a dictionary term.</field>
<field name="att.patternReplacement" gloss="">provides attributes for regular-expression matching and replacement.</field>
<field name="att.personal" gloss="attributes for components of names usually, but not necessarily, personal names">common attributes for those elements which form part of a name usually, but not necessarily, a personal name.</field>
<field name="att.placement" gloss="">provides attributes for describing where on the source page or object a textual element appears.</field>
<field name="att.pointing.group" gloss="target function">provides a set of attributes common to all elements which enclose groups of pointer elements.</field>
<field name="att.pointing" gloss="">provides a set of attributes used by all elements which point to other elements by means of one or more URI references.</field>
<field name="att.ptrLike.form" gloss="form pointers">provides attributes which indicate the orthographic or pronunciation forms of the headword in a dictionary.</field>
<field name="att.ranging" gloss="">provides attributes for describing numerical ranges.</field>
<field name="att.rdgPart" gloss="witness or witnesses">provides attributes to mark the beginning or ending of a fragmentary manuscript or other witness.</field>
<field name="att.repeatable" gloss="minimum number of occurences">supplies attributes for the elements which define component parts of a content model.</field>
<field name="att.resourced" gloss="uniform resource locator">provides attributes by which a resource (such as an externally held media file) may be located.</field>
<field name="att.scoping" gloss="">provides attributes for selecting particular elements within a document.</field>
<field name="att.segLike" gloss="">provides attributes for elements used for arbitrary segmentation.</field>
<field name="att.sortable" gloss="">provides attributes for elements in lists or groups that are sortable, but whose sorting key cannot be derived mechanically from the element content.</field>
<field name="att.spanning" gloss="">provides attributes for elements which delimit a span of text by pointing mechanisms rather than by enclosing it.</field>
<field name="att.styleDef" gloss="">provides attributes to specify the name of a formal definition language used to provide formatting or rendition information.</field>
<field name="att.tableDecoration" gloss="columns">provides attributes used to decorate rows or cells of a table.</field>
<field name="att.textCritical" gloss="variant sequence">defines a set of attributes common to all elements representing variant readings in text critical work.</field>
<field name="att.timed" gloss="">provides attributes common to those elements which have a duration in time, expressed either absolutely or by reference to an alignment map.</field>
<field name="att.transcriptional" gloss="sequence">provides attributes specific to elements encoding authorial or scribal intervention in a text when transcribing manuscript or similar sources.</field>
<field name="att.translatable" gloss="">provides attributes used to indicate the status of a translatable portion of an ODD document.</field>
<field name="att.typed" gloss="">provides attributes which can be used to classify or subclassify elements in any way.</field>
<field name="att.witnessed" gloss="witness or witnesses">supplies the attribute used to identify the witnesses supporting a particular reading in a critical apparatus.</field>
<field name="att.written" gloss="">provides an attribute to indicate the hand in which the content of an element was written in the source being transcribed.</field>
<field name="att" gloss="attribute">contains the name of an attribute appearing within running text.</field>
<field name="attDef" gloss="attribute definition">contains the definition of a single attribute.</field>
<field name="attList" gloss="organization">contains documentation for all the attributes associated with this element, as a series of <gi>attDef</gi> elements.</field>
<field name="attRef" gloss="attribute pointer">points to the definition of an attribute or group of attributes.</field>
<field name="author" gloss="">in a bibliographic reference, contains the name(s) of an author, personal or corporate, of a work; for example in the same form as that provided by a recognized bibliographic name authority.</field>
<field name="authority" gloss="release authority">supplies the name of a person or other agency responsible for making a work available, other than a publisher or distributor.</field>
<field name="availability" gloss="">supplies information about the availability of a text, for example any restrictions on its use or distribution, its copyright status, any licence applying to it, etc.</field>
<field name="back" gloss="back matter">contains any appendixes, etc. following the main part of a text.</field>
<field name="bibl" gloss="bibliographic citation">contains a loosely-structured bibliographic citation of which the sub-components may or may not be explicitly tagged.</field>
<field name="biblFull" gloss="fully-structured bibliographic citation">contains a fully-structured bibliographic citation, in which all components of the TEI file description are present.</field>
<field name="biblScope" gloss="scope of bibliographic reference">defines the scope of a bibliographic reference, for example as a list of page numbers, or a named subdivision of a larger work.</field>
<field name="biblStruct" gloss="structured bibliographic citation">contains a structured bibliographic citation, in which only bibliographic sub-elements appear and in a specified order.</field>
<field name="bicond" gloss="bi-conditional feature-structure constraint">defines a biconditional feature-structure constraint; both consequent and antecedent are specified as feature structures or groups of feature structures; the constraint is satisfied if both subsume a given feature structure, or if both do not.</field>
<field name="binary" gloss="binary value">represents the value part of a feature-value specification which can contain either of exactly two possible values.</field>
<field name="binaryObject" gloss="">provides encoded binary data representing an inline graphic, audio, video or other object.</field>
<field name="binding" gloss="">contains a description of one binding, i.e. type of covering, boards, etc. applied to a manuscript or other object.</field>
<field name="bindingDesc" gloss="binding description">describes the present and former bindings of a manuscript or other object, either as a series of paragraphs or as a series of distinct <gi>binding</gi> elements, one for each binding of the manuscript.</field>
<field name="birth" gloss="caesarean section">contains information about a person's birth, such as its date and place.</field>
<field name="bloc" gloss="">contains the name of a geo-political unit consisting of two or more nation states or countries.</field>
<field name="body" gloss="text body">contains the whole body of a single unitary text, excluding any front or back matter.</field>
<field name="broadcast" gloss="">describes a broadcast used as the source of a spoken text.</field>
<field name="byline" gloss="">contains the primary statement of responsibility given for a work on its title page or at the head or end of the work.</field>
<field name="c" gloss="character">represents a character.</field>
<field name="caesura" gloss="">marks the point at which a metrical line may be divided.</field>
<field name="calendar" gloss="">describes a calendar or dating system used in a dating formula in the text.</field>
<field name="calendarDesc" gloss="calendar description">contains a description of the calendar system used in any dating expression found in the text.</field>
<field name="camera" gloss="">describes a particular camera angle or viewpoint in a screen play.</field>
<field name="caption" gloss="">contains the text of a caption or other text displayed as part of a film script or screenplay.</field>
<field name="case" gloss="">contains grammatical case information given by a dictionary for a given form.</field>
<field name="castGroup" gloss="cast list grouping">groups one or more individual <gi>castItem</gi> elements within a cast list.</field>
<field name="castItem" gloss="cast list item">contains a single entry within a cast list, describing either a single role or a list of non-speaking roles.</field>
<field name="castList" gloss="cast list">contains a single cast list or dramatis personae.</field>
<field name="catchwords" gloss="">describes the system used to ensure correct ordering of the quires or similar making up a codex, incunable, or other object typically by means of annotations at the foot of the page.</field>
<field name="catDesc" gloss="category description">describes some category within a taxonomy or text typology, either in the form of a brief prose description or in terms of the situational parameters used by the TEI formal <gi>textDesc</gi>.</field>
<field name="category" gloss="">contains an individual descriptive category, possibly nested within a superordinate category, within a user-defined taxonomy.</field>
<field name="catRef" gloss="category reference">specifies one or more defined categories within some taxonomy or text typology.</field>
<field name="cb" gloss="column beginning">marks the beginning of a new column of a text on a multi-column page.</field>
<field name="cell" gloss="">contains one cell of a table.</field>
<field name="certainty" gloss="certainty">indicates the degree of certainty associated with some aspect of the text markup.</field>
<field name="change" gloss="">documents a change or set of changes made during the production of a source document, or during the revision of an electronic file.</field>
<field name="channel" gloss="primary channel">describes the medium or channel by which a text is delivered or experienced. For a written text, this might be print, manuscript, email, etc.; for a spoken one, radio, telephone, face-to-face, etc.</field>
<field name="char" gloss="character">provides descriptive information about a character<!-- which is not otherwise available in the document character set-->.</field>
<field name="charDecl" gloss="character declarations">provides information about nonstandard characters and glyphs.</field>
<field name="charName" gloss="character name">contains the name of a character, expressed following Unicode conventions.</field>
<field name="charProp" gloss="character property">provides a name and value for some property of the parent character or glyph.</field>
<field name="choice" gloss="">groups a number of alternative encodings for the same point in a text.</field>
<field name="cit" gloss="cited quotation">contains a quotation from some other document, together with a bibliographic reference to its source. In a dictionary it may contain an example text with at least one occurrence of the word form, used in the sense being described, or a translation of the headword, or an example.</field>
<field name="citedRange" gloss="cited range">defines the range of cited content, often represented by pages or other units</field>
<field name="cl" gloss="clause">represents a grammatical clause.</field>
<field name="classCode" gloss="classification code">contains the classification code used for this text in some standard classification system.</field>
<field name="classDecl" gloss="classification declarations">contains one or more taxonomies defining any classificatory codes used elsewhere in the text.</field>
<field name="classes" gloss="">specifies all the classes of which the documented element or class is a member or subclass.</field>
<field name="classRef" gloss="">points to the specification for an attribute or model class which is to be included in a schema</field>
<field name="classSpec" gloss="class specification">contains reference information for a TEI element class; that is a group of elements which appear together in content models, or which share some common attribute, or both.</field>
<field name="climate" gloss="">contains information about the physical climate of a place.</field>
<field name="closer" gloss="">groups together salutations, datelines, and similar phrases appearing as a final group at the end of a division, especially of a letter.</field>
<field name="code" gloss="formal language">contains literal code from some formal language such as a programming language.</field>
<field name="collation" gloss="">contains a description of how the leaves, bifolia, or similar objects are physically arranged.</field>
<field name="collection" gloss="">contains the name of a collection of manuscripts or other objects, not necessarily located within a single repository.</field>
<field name="colloc" gloss="collocate">contains any sequence of words that co-occur with the headword with significant frequency.</field>
<field name="colophon" gloss="">contains the <term>colophon</term> of an item: that is, a statement providing information regarding the date, place, agency, or reason for production of the manuscript or other object.</field>
<field name="cond" gloss="conditional feature-structure constraint">defines a conditional feature-structure constraint; the consequent and the antecedent are specified as feature structures or feature-structure collections; the constraint is satisfied if both the antecedent and the consequent subsume a given feature structure, or if the antecedent does not.</field>
<field name="condition" gloss="">contains a description of the physical condition of the manuscript or object.</field>
<field name="constitution" gloss="fragments">describes the internal composition of a text or text sample, for example as fragmentary, complete, etc.</field>
<field name="constraint" gloss="constraint rules">the formal rules of a constraint</field>
<field name="constraintSpec" gloss="constraint on schema">contains a formal constraint, typically expressed in a rule-based schema language, to which a construct must conform in order to be considered valid<!--ebb: old description of 2009-06-10 was: "contains a constraint, expressed in some formal syntax, which cannot be expressed in the structural content model"--></field>
<field name="content" gloss="content model">contains a declaration of the intended content model for the element (or other construct) being specified.</field>
<field name="corr" gloss="correction">contains the correct form of a passage apparently erroneous in the copy text.</field>
<field name="correction" gloss="correction principles">states how and under what circumstances corrections have been made in the text.</field>
<field name="correspAction" gloss="correspondence action">contains a structured description of the place, the name of a person/organization and the date related to the sending/receiving of a message or any other action related to the correspondence.</field>
<field name="correspContext" gloss="correspondence context">provides references to preceding or following correspondence related to this piece of correspondence.</field>
<field name="correspDesc" gloss="">contains a description of the actions related to one act of correspondence.</field>
<field name="country" gloss="">contains the name of a geo-political unit, such as a nation, country, colony, or commonwealth, larger than or administratively superior to a region and smaller than a bloc.</field>
<field name="creation" gloss="">contains information about the creation of a text.</field>
<field name="cRefPattern" gloss="canonical reference pattern">specifies an expression and replacement pattern for transforming a canonical reference into a URI.</field>
<field name="custEvent" gloss="custodial event">describes a single event during the custodial history of a manuscript or other object.</field>
<field name="custodialHist" gloss="custodial history">contains a description of a manuscript or other object's custodial history, either as running prose or as a series of dated custodial events.</field>
<field name="damage" gloss="">contains an area of damage to the text witness.</field>
<field name="damageSpan" gloss="damaged span of text">marks the beginning of a longer sequence of text which is damaged in some way but still legible.</field>
<field name="dataFacet" gloss="">Restricts the value of the strings used to represent values of a datatype, according to <ref target="#XSD2">XML Schemas: Part 2: Datatypes</ref>. </field>
<field name="dataRef" gloss="">identifies the datatype of an attribute value, either by referencing an item in an externally defined datatype library, or by pointing to a TEI-defined data specification</field>
<field name="dataSpec" gloss="datatype specification">documents a datatype.</field>
<field name="datatype" gloss="">specifies the declared value for an attribute, by referring to any datatype defined by the chosen schema language.</field>
<field name="date" gloss="">contains a date in any format.</field>
<field name="dateline" gloss="">contains a brief description of the place, date, time, etc. of production of a letter, newspaper story, or other work, prefixed or suffixed to it as a kind of heading or trailer.</field>
<field name="death" gloss="">contains information about a person's death, such as its date and place.</field>
<field name="decoDesc" gloss="decoration description">contains a description of the decoration of a manuscript or other object, either as in paragraphs, or as one or more <gi>decoNote</gi> elements.</field>
<field name="decoNote" gloss="note on decoration">contains a note describing either a decorative component of a manuscript or other object, or a fairly homogenous class of such components.</field>
<field name="def" gloss="definition">contains definition text in a dictionary entry.</field>
<field name="default" gloss="default feature value">represents the value part of a feature-value specification which contains a defaulted value.</field>
<field name="defaultVal" gloss="default value">specifies the default declared value for an attribute.</field>
<field name="del" gloss="deletion">contains a letter, word, or passage deleted, marked as deleted, or otherwise indicated as superfluous or spurious in the copy text by an author, scribe, or a previous annotator or corrector.</field>
<field name="delSpan" gloss="deleted span of text">marks the beginning of a longer sequence of text deleted, marked as deleted, or otherwise signaled as superfluous or spurious by an author, scribe, annotator, or corrector.</field>
<field name="depth" gloss="">contains a measurement measured across the spine of a book or codex, or (for other text-bearing objects) perpendicular to the measurement given by the <gi>width</gi> element.</field>
<field name="derivation" gloss="">describes the nature and extent of originality of this text.</field>
<field name="desc" gloss="description">contains a brief description of the object documented by its parent element, typically a documentation element or an entity.</field>
<field name="dictScrap" gloss="dictionary scrap">encloses a part of a dictionary entry in which other phrase-level dictionary elements are freely combined.</field>
<field name="dim" gloss="">contains any single measurement forming part of a dimensional specification of some sort.</field>
<field name="dimensions" gloss="">contains a dimensional specification.</field>
<field name="distinct" gloss="">identifies any word or phrase which is regarded as linguistically distinct, for example as archaic, technical, dialectal, non-preferred, etc., or as forming part of a sublanguage.</field>
<field name="distributor" gloss="">supplies the name of a person or other agency responsible for the distribution of a text.</field>
<field name="district" gloss="">contains the name of any kind of subdivision of a settlement, such as a parish, ward, or other administrative or geographic unit.</field>
<field name="div" gloss="text division">contains a subdivision of the front, body, or back of a text.</field>
<field name="div1" gloss="level-1 text division">contains a first-level subdivision of the front, body, or back of a text.</field>
<field name="div2" gloss="level-2 text division">contains a second-level subdivision of the front, body, or back of a text.</field>
<field name="div3" gloss="level-3 text division">contains a third-level subdivision of the front, body, or back of a text.</field>
<field name="div4" gloss="level-4 text division">contains a fourth-level subdivision of the front, body, or back of a text.</field>
<field name="div5" gloss="level-5 text division">contains a fifth-level subdivision of the front, body, or back of a text.</field>
<field name="div6" gloss="level-6 text division">contains a sixth-level subdivision of the front, body, or back of a text.</field>
<field name="div7" gloss="level-7 text division">contains the smallest possible subdivision of the front, body or back of a text, larger than a paragraph.</field>
<field name="divGen" gloss="automatically generated text division">indicates the location at which a textual division generated automatically by a text-processing application is to appear.</field>
<field name="docAuthor" gloss="document author">contains the name of the author of the document, as given on the title page (often but not always contained in a byline).</field>
<field name="docDate" gloss="document date">contains the date of a document, as given on a title page or in a dateline.</field>
<field name="docEdition" gloss="document edition">contains an edition statement as presented on a title page of a document.</field>
<field name="docImprint" gloss="document imprint">contains the imprint statement (place and date of publication, publisher name), as given (usually) at the foot of a title page.</field>
<field name="docTitle" gloss="document title">contains the title of a document, including all its constituents, as given on a title page.</field>
<field name="domain" gloss="domain of use">describes the most important social context in which the text was realized or for which it is intended, for example private vs. public, education, religion, etc.</field>
<field name="edition" gloss="">describes the particularities of one edition of a text.</field>
<field name="editionStmt" gloss="edition statement">groups information relating to one edition of a text.</field>
<field name="editor" gloss="">contains a secondary statement of responsibility for a bibliographic item, for example the name of an individual, institution or organization, (or of several such) acting as editor, compiler, translator, etc.</field>
<field name="editorialDecl" gloss="editorial practice declaration">provides details of editorial principles and practices applied during the encoding of a text.</field>
<field name="education" gloss="">contains a description of the educational experience of a person.</field>
<field name="eg" gloss="example">contains any kind of illustrative example.</field>
<field name="egXML" gloss="example of XML">a single XML fragment demonstrating the use of some XML, such as elements, attributes, or processing instructions, etc., in which the <gi>egXML</gi> element functions as the root element.</field>
<field name="eLeaf" gloss="leaf or terminal node of an embedding tree">provides explicitly for a leaf of an embedding tree, which may also be encoded with the <gi>eTree</gi> element.</field>
<field name="elementRef" gloss="">points to the specification for some element which is to be included in a schema</field>
<field name="elementSpec" gloss="element specification">documents the structure, content, and purpose of a single element type.</field>
<field name="email" gloss="electronic mail address">contains an email address identifying a location to which email messages can be delivered.</field>
<field name="emph" gloss="emphasized">marks words or phrases which are stressed or emphasized for linguistic or rhetorical effect.</field>
<field name="empty" gloss="">indicates the presence of an empty node within a content model</field>
<field name="encodingDesc" gloss="encoding description">documents the relationship between an electronic text and the source or sources from which it was derived.</field>
<field name="entry" gloss="">contains a single structured entry in any kind of lexical resource, such as a dictionary or lexicon.</field>
<field name="entryFree" gloss="unstructured entry">contains a single unstructured entry in any kind of lexical resource, such as a dictionary or lexicon.</field>
<field name="epigraph" gloss="">contains a quotation, anonymous or attributed, appearing at the start or end of a section or on a title page.</field>
<field name="epilogue" gloss="">contains the epilogue to a drama, typically spoken by an actor out of character, possibly in association with a particular performance or venue.</field>
<field name="equipment" gloss="">provides technical details of the equipment and media used for an audio or video recording used as the source for a spoken text.</field>
<field name="equiv" gloss="equivalent">specifies a component which is considered equivalent to the parent element, either by co-reference, or by external link.</field>
<field name="eTree" gloss="embedding tree">provides an alternative to the <gi>tree</gi> element for representing ordered rooted tree structures.</field>
<field name="etym" gloss="etymology">encloses the etymological information in a dictionary entry.</field>
<field name="event" gloss="">contains data relating to any kind of significant event associated with a person, place, or organization.</field>
<field name="ex" gloss="editorial expansion">contains a sequence of letters added by an editor or transcriber when expanding an abbreviation.</field>
<field name="exemplum" gloss="">groups an example demonstrating the use of an element along with optional paragraphs of commentary.</field>
<field name="expan" gloss="expansion">contains the expansion of an abbreviation.</field>
<field name="explicit" gloss="">contains the <term>explicit</term> of a item, that is, the closing words of the text proper, exclusive of any rubric or colophon which might follow it.</field>
<field name="extent" gloss="">describes the approximate size of a text stored on some carrier medium or of some other object, digital or non-digital, specified in any convenient units.</field>
<field name="f" gloss="feature">represents a <term>feature value specification</term>, that is, the association of a name with a value of any of several different types.</field>
<field name="facsimile" gloss="">contains a representation of some written source in the form of a set of images rather than as transcribed or encoded text.</field>
<field name="factuality" gloss="">describes the extent to which the text may be regarded as imaginative or non-imaginative, that is, as describing a fictional or a non-fictional world.</field>
<field name="faith" gloss="">specifies the faith, religion, or belief set of a person.</field>
<field name="fDecl" gloss="feature declaration">declares a single feature, specifying its name, organization, range of allowed values, and optionally its default value.</field>
<field name="fDescr" gloss="feature description (in FSD)">describes in prose what is represented by the feature being declared and its values.</field>
<field name="figDesc" gloss="description of figure">contains a brief prose description of the appearance or content of a graphic figure, for use when documenting an image without displaying it.</field>
<field name="figure" gloss="">groups elements representing or containing graphic information such as an illustration, formula, or figure.</field>
<field name="fileDesc" gloss="file description">contains a full bibliographic description of an electronic file.</field>
<field name="filiation" gloss="">contains information concerning the manuscript or other object's <term>filiation</term>, i.e. its relationship to other surviving manuscripts or other objects of the same text or contents, its <term>protographs</term>, <term>antigraphs</term> and <term>apographs</term>.</field>
<field name="finalRubric" gloss="">contains the string of words that denotes the end of a text division, often with an assertion as to its author and title, usually set off from the text itself by red ink, by a different size or type of script, or by some other such visual device.</field>
<field name="fLib" gloss="feature library">assembles a library of <gi>f</gi> (feature) elements.</field>
<field name="floatingText" gloss="">contains a single text of any kind, whether unitary or composite, which interrupts the text containing it at any point and after which the surrounding text resumes.</field>
<field name="floruit" gloss="">contains information about a person's period of activity.</field>
<field name="foliation" gloss="">describes the numbering system or systems used to count the leaves or pages in a codex or similar object.</field>
<field name="foreign" gloss="">identifies a word or phrase as belonging to some language other than that of the surrounding text.</field>
<field name="forename" gloss="">contains a forename, given or baptismal name.</field>
<field name="forest" gloss="">provides for groups of rooted trees.</field>
<field name="form" gloss="form information group">groups all the information on the written and spoken forms of one headword.</field>
<field name="formula" gloss="">contains a mathematical or other formula.</field>
<field name="front" gloss="front matter">contains any prefatory matter (headers, abstracts, title page, prefaces, dedications, etc.) found at the start of a document, before the main body.</field>
<field name="fs" gloss="feature structure">represents a <term>feature structure</term>, that is, a collection of feature-value pairs organized as a structural unit.</field>
<field name="fsConstraints" gloss="feature-structure constraints">specifies constraints on the content of valid feature structures.</field>
<field name="fsdDecl" gloss="feature system declaration">provides a feature system declaration comprising one or more feature structure declarations or feature structure declaration links.</field>
<field name="fsDecl" gloss="feature structure declaration">declares one type of feature structure.</field>
<field name="fsDescr" gloss="feature system description (in FSD)">describes in prose what is represented by the type of feature structure declared in the enclosing fsDecl.</field>
<field name="fsdLink" gloss="feature structure declaration link">associates the name of a typed feature structure with a feature structure declaration for it.</field>
<field name="funder" gloss="funding body">specifies the name of an individual, institution, or organization responsible for the funding of a project or text.</field>
<field name="fvLib" gloss="feature-value library">assembles a library of reusable feature value elements (including complete feature structures).</field>
<field name="fw" gloss="forme work">contains a running head (e.g. a header, footer), catchword, or similar material appearing on the current page.</field>
<field name="g" gloss="character or glyph">represents a glyph, or a non-standard character.</field>
<field name="gap" gloss="">indicates a point where material has been omitted in a transcription, whether for editorial reasons described in the TEI header, as part of sampling practice, or because the material is illegible, invisible, or inaudible.</field>
<field name="gb" gloss="gathering beginning">marks the beginning of a new gathering or quire in a transcribed codex.</field>
<field name="gen" gloss="gender">identifies the morphological gender of a lexical item, as given in the dictionary.</field>
<field name="genName" gloss="generational name component">contains a name component used to distinguish otherwise similar names on the basis of the relative ages or generations of the persons named.</field>
<field name="geo" gloss="geographical coordinates">contains any expression of a set of geographic coordinates, representing a point, line, or area on the surface of the earth in some notation.</field>
<field name="geoDecl" gloss="geographic coordinates declaration">documents the notation and the datum used for geographic coordinates expressed as content of the <gi>geo</gi> element elsewhere within the document.</field>
<field name="geogFeat" gloss="geographical feature name">contains a common noun identifying some geographical feature contained within a geographic name, such as valley, mount, etc.</field>
<field name="geogName" gloss="geographical name">identifies a name associated with some geographical feature such as Windrush Valley or Mount Sinai.</field>
<field name="gi" gloss="element name">contains the name (generic identifier) of an element.</field>
<field name="gloss" gloss="">identifies a phrase or word used to provide a gloss or definition for some other word or phrase.</field>
<field name="glyph" gloss="character glyph">provides descriptive information about a character glyph<!-- which is not otherwise available in the document character set-->.</field>
<field name="glyphName" gloss="character glyph name">contains the name of a glyph, expressed following Unicode conventions for character names.</field>
<field name="gram" gloss="grammatical information">within an entry in a dictionary or a terminological data file, contains grammatical information relating to a term, word, or form.</field>
<field name="gramGrp" gloss="grammatical information group">groups morpho-syntactic information about a lexical item, e.g. <gi>pos</gi>, <gi>gen</gi>, <gi>number</gi>, <gi>case</gi>, or <gi>iType</gi> (inflectional class).</field>
<field name="graph" gloss="">encodes a graph, which is a collection of nodes, and arcs which connect the nodes.</field>
<field name="graphic" gloss="">indicates the location of a graphic or illustration, either forming part of a text, or providing an image of it.</field>
<field name="group" gloss="">contains the body of a composite text, grouping together a sequence of distinct texts (or groups of such texts) which are regarded as a unit for some purpose, for example the collected works of an author, a sequence of prose essays, etc.</field>
<field name="handDesc" gloss="description of hands">contains a description of all the different hands used in a manuscript or other object.</field>
<field name="handNote" gloss="note on hand">describes a particular style or hand distinguished within a manuscript.</field>
<field name="handNotes" gloss="">contains one or more <gi>handNote</gi> elements documenting the different hands identified within the source texts.</field>
<field name="handShift" gloss="">marks the beginning of a sequence of text written in a new hand, or the beginning of a scribal stint.</field>
<field name="head" gloss="heading">contains any type of heading, for example the title of a section, or the heading of a list, glossary, manuscript description, etc.</field>
<field name="headItem" gloss="heading for list items">contains the heading for the item or gloss column in a glossary list or similar structured list.</field>
<field name="headLabel" gloss="heading for list labels">contains the heading for the label or term column in a glossary list or similar structured list.</field>
<field name="height" gloss="">contains a measurement measured along the axis at right angles to the bottom of the written surface, i.e. parallel to the spine for a codex or book.</field>
<field name="heraldry" gloss="">contains a heraldic formula or phrase, typically found as part of a blazon, coat of arms, etc. </field>
<field name="hi" gloss="highlighted">marks a word or phrase as graphically distinct from the surrounding text, for reasons concerning which no claim is made.</field>
<field name="history" gloss=""> groups elements describing the full history of a manuscript, manuscript part, or other object.</field>
<field name="hom" gloss="homograph">groups information relating to one homograph within an entry.</field>
<field name="hyph" gloss="hyphenation">contains a hyphenated form of a dictionary headword, or hyphenation information in some other form.</field>
<field name="hyphenation" gloss="end-of-line">summarizes the way in which hyphenation in a source text has been treated in an encoded version of it.</field>
<field name="ident" gloss="identifier">contains an identifier or name for an object of some kind in a formal language. <gi>ident</gi> is used for tokens such as variable names, class names, type names, function names etc. in formal programming languages.</field>
<field name="idno" gloss="identifier">supplies any form of identifier used to identify some object, such as a bibliographic item, a person, a title, an organization, etc. in a standardized way.</field>
<field name="if" gloss="">defines a conditional default value for a feature; the condition is specified as a feature structure, and is met if it subsumes the feature structure in the text for which a default value is sought.</field>
<field name="iff" gloss="if and only if">separates the condition from the consequence in a <gi>bicond</gi> element.</field>
<field name="imprimatur" gloss="">contains a formal statement authorizing the publication of a work, sometimes required to appear on a title page or its verso.</field>
<field name="imprint" gloss="">groups information relating to the publication or distribution of a bibliographic item.</field>
<field name="incident" gloss="">marks any phenomenon or occurrence, not necessarily vocalized or communicative, for example incidental noises or other events affecting communication.</field>
<field name="incipit" gloss="">contains the <term>incipit</term> of a manuscript or similar object item, that is the opening words of the text proper, exclusive of any <term>rubric</term> which might precede it, of sufficient length to identify the work uniquely; such incipits were, in former times, frequently used a means of reference to a work, in place of a title.</field>
<field name="index" gloss="index entry">marks a location to be indexed for whatever purpose.</field>
<field name="iNode" gloss="intermediate (or internal) node">represents an intermediate (or internal) node of a tree.</field>
<field name="institution" gloss="">contains the name of an organization such as a university or library, with which a manuscript or other object is identified, generally its holding institution.</field>
<field name="interaction" gloss="">describes the extent, cardinality and nature of any interaction among those producing and experiencing the text, for example in the form of response or interjection, commentary, etc.</field>
<field name="interp" gloss="interpretation">summarizes a specific interpretative annotation which can be linked to a span of text.</field>
<field name="interpGrp" gloss="interpretation group">collects together a set of related interpretations which share responsibility or type.</field>
<field name="interpretation" gloss="">describes the scope of any analytic or interpretive information added to the text in addition to the transcription.</field>
<field name="item" gloss="">contains one component of a list.</field>
<field name="iType" gloss="inflectional class">indicates the inflectional class associated with a lexical item.</field>
<field name="join" gloss="">identifies a possibly fragmented segment of text, by pointing at the possibly discontiguous elements which compose it.</field>
<field name="joinGrp" gloss="join group">groups a collection of <gi>join</gi> elements and possibly pointers.</field>
<field name="keywords" gloss="">contains a list of keywords or phrases identifying the topic or nature of a text.</field>
<field name="kinesic" gloss="">marks any communicative phenomenon, not necessarily vocalized, for example a gesture, frown, etc.</field>
<field name="l" gloss="verse line">contains a single, possibly incomplete, line of verse.</field>
<field name="label" gloss="">contains any label or heading used to identify part of a text, typically but not exclusively in a list or glossary.</field>
<field name="lacunaEnd" gloss="">indicates the end of a lacuna in a mostly complete textual witness.</field>
<field name="lacunaStart" gloss="">indicates the beginning of a lacuna in the text of a mostly complete textual witness.</field>
<field name="lang" gloss="language name">contains the name of a language mentioned in etymological or other linguistic discussion.</field>
<field name="langKnowledge" gloss="language knowledge">summarizes the state of a person's linguistic knowledge, either as prose or by a list of <gi>langKnown</gi> elements.</field>
<field name="langKnown" gloss="language known">summarizes the state of a person's linguistic competence, i.e., knowledge of a single language.</field>
<field name="language" gloss="identifier">characterizes a single language or sublanguage used within a text.</field>
<field name="langUsage" gloss="language usage">describes the languages, sublanguages, registers, dialects, etc. represented within a text.</field>
<field name="layout" gloss="textual streams">describes how text is laid out on the page or surface of the object, including information about any ruling, pricking, or other evidence of page-preparation techniques.</field>
<field name="layoutDesc" gloss="layout description">collects the set of layout descriptions applicable to a manuscript or other object.</field>
<field name="lb" gloss="line beginning">marks the beginning of a new (typographic) line in some edition or version of a text.</field>
<field name="lbl" gloss="label">contains a label for a form, example, translation, or other piece of information, e.g. abbreviation for, contraction of, literally, approximately, synonyms:, etc.</field>
<field name="leaf" gloss="">encodes the leaves (terminal nodes) of a tree.</field>
<field name="lem" gloss="lemma">contains the lemma, or base text, of a textual variation.</field>
<field name="lg" gloss="line group">contains one or more verse lines functioning as a formal unit, e.g. a stanza, refrain, verse paragraph, etc.</field>
<field name="licence" gloss="">contains information about a licence or other legal agreement applicable to the text.</field>
<field name="line" gloss="">contains the transcription of a topographic line in the source document</field>
<field name="link" gloss="">defines an association or hypertextual link among elements or passages, of some type not more precisely specifiable by other elements.</field>
<field name="linkGrp" gloss="link group">defines a collection of associations or hypertextual links.</field>
<field name="list" gloss="">contains any sequence of items organized as a list.</field>
<field name="listApp" gloss="list of apparatus entries">contains a list of apparatus entries.</field>
<field name="listBibl" gloss="citation list">contains a list of bibliographic citations of any kind.</field>
<field name="listChange" gloss="">groups a number of change descriptions associated with either the creation of a source text or the revision of an encoded text.</field>
<field name="listEvent" gloss="list of events">contains a list of descriptions, each of which provides information about an identifiable event.</field>
<field name="listForest" gloss="">provides for lists of forests.</field>
<field name="listNym" gloss="list of canonical names">contains a list of nyms, that is, standardized names for any thing.</field>
<field name="listObject" gloss="list of objects">contains a list of descriptions, each of which provides information about an identifiable physical object.</field>
<field name="listOrg" gloss="list of organizations">contains a list of elements, each of which provides information about an identifiable organization.</field>
<field name="listPerson" gloss="list of persons">contains a list of descriptions, each of which provides information about an identifiable person or a group of people, for example the participants in a language interaction, or the people referred to in a historical source.</field>
<field name="listPlace" gloss="list of places">contains a list of places, optionally followed by a list of relationships (other than containment) defined amongst them.</field>
<field name="listPrefixDef" gloss="list of prefix definitions">contains a list of definitions of prefixing schemes used in <ident type="datatype">data.pointer</ident> values, showing how abbreviated URIs using each scheme may be expanded into full URIs.</field>
<field name="listRef" gloss="list of references">supplies a list of significant references to places where this element is discussed, in the current document or elsewhere.</field>
<field name="listRelation" gloss="">provides information about relationships identified amongst people, places, and organizations, either informally as prose or as formally expressed relation links.</field>
<field name="listState" gloss="list of states and/or traits">contains a list of various kinds of characteristics of people, places, and organizations.</field>
<field name="listTranspose" gloss="">supplies a list of transpositions, each of which is indicated at some point in a document typically by means of metamarks.</field>
<field name="listWit" gloss="witness list">lists definitions for all the witnesses referred to by a critical apparatus, optionally grouped hierarchically.</field>
<field name="locale" gloss="">contains a brief informal description of the kind of place concerned, for example: a room, a restaurant, a park bench, etc.</field>
<field name="localName" gloss="locally-defined property name">contains a locally defined name for some property.</field>
<field name="location" gloss="">defines the location of a place as a set of geographical coordinates, in terms of other named geo-political entities, or as an address.</field>
<field name="locus" gloss="">defines a location within a manuscript, manuscript part, or other object typically as a (possibly discontinuous) sequence of folio references.</field>
<field name="locusGrp" gloss="">groups a number of locations which together form a distinct but discontinuous item within a manuscript, manuscript part, or other object.</field>
<field name="m" gloss="morpheme">represents a grammatical morpheme.</field>
<field name="macro.limitedContent" gloss="paragraph content">defines the content of prose elements that are not used for transcription of extant materials.</field>
<field name="macro.paraContent" gloss="paragraph content">defines the content of paragraphs and similar elements.</field>
<field name="macro.phraseSeq.limited" gloss="limited phrase sequence">defines a sequence of character data and those phrase-level elements that are not typically used for transcribing extant documents.</field>
<field name="macro.phraseSeq" gloss="phrase sequence">defines a sequence of character data and phrase-level elements.</field>
<field name="macro.specialPara" gloss="'special' paragraph content">defines the content model of elements such as notes or list items, which either contain a series of component-level elements or else have the same structure as a paragraph, containing a series of phrase-level and inter-level elements.</field>
<field name="macro.xtext" gloss="extended text">defines a sequence of character data and gaiji elements.</field>
<field name="macroRef" gloss="">points to the specification for some pattern which is to be included in a schema</field>
<field name="macroSpec" gloss="macro specification">documents the function and implementation of a pattern.</field>
<field name="mapping" gloss="character mapping">contains one or more 	 characters which are related to the parent character or glyph 	 in some respect, as specified by the <att>type</att> 	 attribute. </field>
<field name="material" gloss="">contains a word or phrase describing the material of which the object being described is composed.</field>
<field name="measure" gloss="">contains a word or phrase referring to some quantity of an object or commodity, usually comprising a number, a unit, and a commodity name.</field>
<field name="measureGrp" gloss="measure group">contains a group of dimensional specifications which relate to the same object, for example the height and width of a manuscript page.</field>
<field name="media" gloss="">indicates the location of any form of external media such as an audio or video clip etc.</field>
<field name="meeting" gloss="">contains the formalized descriptive title for a meeting or conference, for use in a bibliographic description for an item derived from such a meeting, or as a heading or preamble to publications emanating from it.</field>
<field name="memberOf" gloss="">specifies class membership of the documented element or class.</field>
<field name="mentioned" gloss="">marks words or phrases mentioned, not used.</field>
<field name="metamark" gloss="">contains or describes any kind of graphic or written signal within a document the function of which is to determine how it should be read rather than forming part of the actual content of the document.</field>
<field name="metDecl" gloss="metrical notation declaration">documents the notation employed to represent a metrical pattern when this is specified as the value of a <att>met</att>, <att>real</att>, or <att>rhyme</att> attribute on any structural element of a metrical text (e.g. <gi>lg</gi>, <gi>l</gi>, or <gi>seg</gi>).</field>
<field name="metSym" gloss="metrical notation symbol">documents the intended significance of a particular character or character sequence within a metrical notation, either explicitly or in terms of other <gi>metSym</gi> elements in the same <gi>metDecl</gi>.</field>
<field name="milestone" gloss="">marks a boundary point separating any kind of section of a text, typically but not necessarily indicating a point at which some part of a standard reference system changes, where the change is not represented by a structural element.</field>
<field name="mod" gloss="">represents any kind of modification identified within a single document.</field>
<field name="model.addressLike" gloss="">groups elements used to represent a postal or email address.</field>
<field name="model.addrPart" gloss="">groups elements such as names or postal codes which may appear as part of a postal<!-- or other form of--> address.</field>
<field name="model.applicationLike" gloss="">groups elements used to record application-specific information about a document in its header.</field>
<field name="model.availabilityPart" gloss="">groups elements such as licences and paragraphs of text which may appear as part of an availability statement</field>
<field name="model.biblLike" gloss="">groups elements containing a bibliographic description.</field>
<field name="model.biblPart" gloss="">groups elements which represent components of a bibliographic description.</field>
<field name="model.castItemPart" gloss="">groups component elements of an entry in a cast list, such as dramatic role or actor's name.</field>
<field name="model.catDescPart" gloss="">groups component elements of the TEI header Category Description.</field>
<field name="model.certLike" gloss="">groups elements which are used to indicate uncertainty or precision of other elements.</field>
<field name="model.choicePart" gloss="">groups elements (other than <gi>choice</gi> itself) which can be used within a <gi>choice</gi> alternation.</field>
<field name="model.common" gloss="">groups common chunk- and inter-level elements.</field>
<field name="model.contentPart" gloss="">groups elements which may appear as part of the content element.</field>
<field name="model.correspActionPart" gloss="">groups elements which define the parts (usually names, dates and places) of one action related to the correspondence.</field>
<field name="model.correspContextPart" gloss="">groups elements which may appear as part of the correspContext element</field>
<field name="model.correspDescPart" gloss="">groups together metadata elements for describing correspondence</field>
<field name="model.dateLike" gloss="">groups elements containing temporal expressions.</field>
<field name="model.descLike" gloss="">groups elements which contain a description of their function.</field>
<field name="model.dimLike" gloss="">groups elements which describe a measurement forming part of the physical dimensions of some object.</field>
<field name="model.div1Like" gloss="">groups top-level structural divisions.</field>
<field name="model.div2Like" gloss="">groups second-level structural divisions.</field>
<field name="model.div3Like" gloss="">groups third-level structural divisions.</field>
<field name="model.div4Like" gloss="">groups fourth-level structural divisions.</field>
<field name="model.div5Like" gloss="">groups fifth-level structural divisions.</field>
<field name="model.div6Like" gloss="">groups sixth-level structural divisions.</field>
<field name="model.div7Like" gloss="">groups seventh-level structural divisions.</field>
<field name="model.divBottom" gloss="">groups elements appearing at the end of a text division<!--(e.g., a <gi>trailer</gi>) with those that can occur either at the beginning or the end (e.g., a <gi>byline</gi>)-->.</field>
<field name="model.divBottomPart" gloss="">groups elements which can occur only at the end of a text division.</field>
<field name="model.divGenLike" gloss="">groups elements used to represent a structural division which is generated rather than explicitly present in the source.</field>
<field name="model.divLike" gloss="">groups elements used to represent un-numbered generic structural divisions.</field>
<field name="model.divPart.spoken" gloss="">groups elements structurally analogous to paragraphs within spoken texts.</field>
<field name="model.divPart" gloss="">groups paragraph-level elements appearing directly within divisions.</field>
<field name="model.divTop" gloss="">groups elements appearing at the beginning of a text division<!--(e.g., <gi>opener</gi>) with those that can occur either at the beginning or the end (e.g., a <gi>byline</gi>)-->.</field>
<field name="model.divTopPart" gloss="">groups elements which can occur only at the beginning of a text division.</field>
<field name="model.divWrapper" gloss="">groups elements which can appear at either top or bottom of a textual division.</field>
<field name="model.editorialDeclPart" gloss="">groups elements which may be used inside <gi>editorialDecl</gi> and appear multiple times.</field>
<field name="model.egLike" gloss="">groups elements containing examples or illustrations.</field>
<field name="model.emphLike" gloss="">groups phrase-level elements which are typographically distinct and to which a specific function can be attributed.</field>
<field name="model.encodingDescPart" gloss="">groups elements which may be used inside <gi>encodingDesc</gi> and appear multiple times.</field>
<field name="model.entryLike" gloss="">groups elements structurally analogous to paragraphs within dictionaries.</field>
<field name="model.entryPart.top" gloss="">groups high level elements within a structured dictionary entry</field>
<field name="model.entryPart" gloss="">groups non-morphological elements appearing within a dictionary entry.</field>
<field name="model.eventLike" gloss="">groups elements which describe events.</field>
<field name="model.featureVal.complex" gloss="">groups elements which express complex feature values in feature structures.</field>
<field name="model.featureVal.single" gloss="">group elements used to represent atomic feature values in feature structures.</field>
<field name="model.featureVal" gloss="">groups elements which represent feature values in feature structures.</field>
<field name="model.formPart" gloss="">groups elements allowed within a <gi>form</gi> element in a dictionary.</field>
<field name="model.frontPart.drama" gloss="">groups elements which appear at the level of divisions within front or back matter of performance texts only.</field>
<field name="model.frontPart" gloss="">groups elements which appear at the level of divisions within front or back matter.</field>
<field name="model.gLike" gloss="">groups elements used to represent individual non-Unicode characters or glyphs.</field>
<field name="model.global.edit" gloss="">groups globally available elements which perform a specifically editorial function.</field>
<field name="model.global.meta" gloss="">groups globally available elements which describe the status of other elements.</field>
<field name="model.global.spoken" gloss="">groups elements which may appear globally within spoken texts.</field>
<field name="model.global" gloss="">groups elements which may appear at any point within a TEI text.</field>
<field name="model.glossLike" gloss="">groups elements which provide an alternative name, explanation, or description for any markup construct.</field>
<field name="model.gramPart" gloss="">groups elements allowed within a <gi>gramGrp</gi> element in a dictionary.</field>
<field name="model.graphicLike" gloss="">groups elements containing images, formulae, and similar objects.</field>
<field name="model.handDescPart" gloss="">groups elements which may be used to describe individual hands distinguished within a manuscript.</field>
<field name="model.headLike" gloss="">groups elements used to provide a title or heading at the start of a text division.</field>
<field name="model.highlighted" gloss="">groups phrase-level elements which are typographically distinct.</field>
<field name="model.hiLike" gloss="">groups phrase-level elements which are typographically distinct but to which no specific function can be attributed.</field>
<field name="model.imprintPart" gloss="">groups the bibliographic elements which occur inside imprints.</field>
<field name="model.inter" gloss="">groups elements which can appear either within or between paragraph-like elements.</field>
<field name="model.labelLike" gloss="">groups elements used to gloss or explain other parts of a document.</field>
<field name="model.lexicalRefinement" gloss="">elements adding further precision to the lexico-grammatical information provided for a dictionary entry.</field>
<field name="model.limitedPhrase" gloss="">groups phrase-level elements excluding those elements primarily intended for transcription of existing sources.</field>
<field name="model.linePart" gloss="">groups transcriptional elements which appear within lines or zones of a source-oriented transcription within a <gi>sourceDoc</gi> element.</field>
<field name="model.listLike" gloss="">groups list-like elements.</field>
<field name="model.lLike" gloss="">groups elements representing metrical components such as verse lines.</field>
<field name="model.lPart" gloss="">groups phrase-level elements which may appear within verse only.</field>
<field name="model.measureLike" gloss="">groups elements which denote a number, a quantity, a measurement, or similar piece of text that conveys some numerical meaning.</field>
<field name="model.milestoneLike" gloss="">groups milestone-style elements used to represent reference systems.</field>
<field name="model.morphLike" gloss="">groups elements which provide morphological information within a dictionary entry.</field>
<field name="model.msItemPart" gloss="">groups elements which can appear within a manuscript item description.</field>
<field name="model.msQuoteLike" gloss="">groups elements which represent passages such as titles quoted from a manuscript as a part of its description.</field>
<field name="model.nameLike.agent" gloss="">groups elements which contain names of individuals or corporate bodies.</field>
<field name="model.nameLike" gloss="">groups elements which name or refer to a person, place, or organization.</field>
<field name="model.noteLike" gloss="">groups globally-available note-like elements.</field>
<field name="model.objectLike" gloss="">groups elements which describe objects.</field>
<field name="model.oddDecl" gloss="">groups elements which generate declarations in some markup language in ODD documents.</field>
<field name="model.oddRef" gloss="">groups elements which reference declarations in some markup language in ODD documents.</field>
<field name="model.offsetLike" gloss="">groups elements which can appear only as part of a place name.</field>
<field name="model.orgPart" gloss="">groups elements which form part of the description of an organization.</field>
<field name="model.orgStateLike" gloss="">groups elements describing changeable characteristics of an organization which have a definite duration.</field>
<field name="model.persEventLike" gloss="">groups elements describing specific events in a person's history, for example birth, marriage, or appointment.</field>
<field name="model.persNamePart" gloss="">groups elements which form part of a personal name.</field>
<field name="model.personLike" gloss="">groups elements which provide information about people and their relationships.</field>
<field name="model.personPart" gloss="">groups elements which form part of the description of a person.</field>
<field name="model.persStateLike" gloss="">groups elements describing changeable characteristics of a person which have a definite duration, for example occupation, residence, or name.</field>
<field name="model.phrase" gloss="">groups elements which can occur at the level of individual words or phrases.</field>
<field name="model.phrase" gloss="">groups phrase-level elements used to encode XML constructs such as element names, attribute names, and attribute values</field>
<field name="model.physDescPart" gloss="">groups specialized elements forming part of the physical description of a manuscript or similar written source.</field>
<field name="model.placeEventLike" gloss="">groups elements which describe events at or affecting a place.</field>
<field name="model.placeLike" gloss="">groups elements used to provide information about places and their relationships.</field>
<field name="model.placeNamePart" gloss="">groups elements which form part of a place name.</field>
<field name="model.placeStateLike" gloss="">groups elements which describe changing states of a place.</field>
<field name="model.pLike.front" gloss="">groups paragraph-like elements which can occur as direct constituents of front matter.</field>
<field name="model.pLike" gloss="">groups paragraph-like elements.</field>
<field name="model.pPart.data" gloss="">groups phrase-level elements containing names, dates, numbers, measures, and similar data.</field>
<field name="model.pPart.edit" gloss="">groups phrase-level elements for simple editorial correction and transcription.</field>
<field name="model.pPart.editorial" gloss="">groups phrase-level elements for simple editorial interventions that may be useful both in transcribing and in authoring.</field>
<field name="model.pPart.msdesc" gloss="">groups phrase-level elements used in manuscript description.</field>
<field name="model.pPart.transcriptional" gloss="">groups phrase-level elements used for editorial transcription of pre-existing source materials.</field>
<field name="model.profileDescPart" gloss="">groups elements which may be used inside <gi>profileDesc</gi> and appear multiple times.</field>
<field name="model.ptrLike.form" gloss="">groups elements used for purposes of location of particular orthographic or pronunciation forms within a dictionary entry.</field>
<field name="model.ptrLike" gloss="">groups elements used for purposes of location and reference.</field>
<field name="model.publicationStmtPart.agency" gloss="">groups the child elements of a <gi>publicationStmt</gi> element of the TEI header that indicate an authorising agent.</field>
<field name="model.publicationStmtPart.detail" gloss="">groups the agency-specific child elements of the <gi>publicationStmt</gi> element of the TEI header.</field>
<field name="model.qLike" gloss="">groups elements related to highlighting which can appear either within or between chunk-level elements.</field>
<field name="model.quoteLike" gloss="">groups elements used to directly contain quotations.</field>
<field name="model.rdgLike" gloss="">groups elements which contain a single reading, other than the lemma, within a textual variation.</field>
<field name="model.rdgPart" gloss="">groups elements which mark the beginning or ending of a fragmentary manuscript or other witness.</field>
<field name="model.recordingPart" gloss="">groups elements used to describe details of an audio or video recording.</field>
<field name="model.resourceLike" gloss="">groups separate elements which constitute the content of a digital resource, as opposed to its metadata.</field>
<field name="model.respLike" gloss="">groups elements which are used to indicate intellectual or other significant responsibility, for example within a bibliographic element.</field>
<field name="model.segLike" gloss="">groups elements used for arbitrary segmentation.</field>
<field name="model.settingPart" gloss="">groups elements used to describe the setting of a linguistic interaction.</field>
<field name="model.sourceDescPart" gloss="">groups elements which may be used inside <gi>sourceDesc</gi> and appear multiple times.</field>
<field name="model.specDescLike" gloss="">groups elements for referring to specification elements.</field>
<field name="model.stageLike" gloss="">groups elements containing stage directions or similar things defined by the module for performance texts.</field>
<field name="model.teiHeaderPart" gloss="">groups high level elements which may appear more than once in a TEI header.</field>
<field name="model.textDescPart" gloss="">groups elements used to categorize a text for example in terms of its situational parameters.</field>
<field name="model.titlepagePart" gloss="">groups elements which can occur as direct constituents of a title page, such as <gi>docTitle</gi>, <gi>docAuthor</gi>, <gi>docImprint</gi>, or <gi>epigraph</gi>.</field>
<field name="model" gloss="">describes the processing intended for a specified element.</field>
<field name="modelGrp" gloss="">any grouping of <gi>model</gi> or <gi>modelSequence</gi> elements with a common output method</field>
<field name="modelSequence" gloss="">any sequence of model or <gi>modelSequence</gi> elements which is to be processed as a single set of actions</field>
<field name="moduleRef" gloss="module reference">references a module which is to be incorporated into a schema.</field>
<field name="moduleSpec" gloss="module specification">documents the structure, content, and purpose of a single module, i.e. a named and externally visible group of declarations.</field>
<field name="monogr" gloss="monographic level">contains bibliographic elements describing an item (e.g. a book or journal) published as an independent item (i.e. as a separate physical object).</field>
<field name="mood" gloss="">contains information about the grammatical mood of verbs (e.g. indicative, subjunctive, imperative).</field>
<field name="move" gloss="movement">marks the actual movement of one or more characters.</field>
<field name="msContents" gloss="manuscript contents">describes the intellectual content of a manuscript, manuscript part, or other object either as a series of paragraphs or as a series of structured manuscript items.</field>
<field name="msDesc" gloss="manuscript description">contains a description of a single identifiable manuscript or other text-bearing object.</field>
<field name="msFrag" gloss="manuscript fragment">contains information about a fragment of a scattered manuscript now held as a single unit or bound into a larger manuscript.</field>
<field name="msIdentifier" gloss="manuscript identifier">contains the information required to identify the manuscript or similar object being described.</field>
<field name="msItem" gloss="manuscript item">describes an individual work or item within the intellectual content of a manuscript, manuscript part, or other object.</field>
<field name="msItemStruct" gloss="structured manuscript item">contains a structured description for an individual work or item within the intellectual content of a manuscript, manuscript part, or other object.</field>
<field name="msName" gloss="alternative name">contains any form of unstructured alternative name used for a manuscript or other object, such as an <soCalled>ocellus nominum</soCalled>, or nickname.</field>
<field name="msPart" gloss="manuscript part">contains information about an originally distinct manuscript or part of a manuscript, which is now part of a composite manuscript.</field>
<field name="musicNotation" gloss="">contains description of type of musical notation.</field>
<field name="name" gloss="name, proper noun">contains a proper noun or noun phrase.</field>
<field name="nameLink" gloss="name link">contains a connecting phrase or link used within a name but not regarded as part of it, such as <mentioned>van der</mentioned> or <mentioned>of</mentioned>.</field>
<field name="namespace" gloss="">supplies the formal name of the namespace to which the elements documented by its children belong.</field>
<field name="nationality" gloss="">contains an informal description of a person's present or past nationality or citizenship.</field>
<field name="node" gloss="adjacent to">encodes a node, a possibly labeled point in a graph.</field>
<field name="normalization" gloss="">indicates the extent of normalization or regularization of the original source carried out in converting it to electronic form.</field>
<field name="notatedMusic" gloss="">encodes the presence of music notation in a text</field>
<field name="note" gloss="">contains a note or annotation.</field>
<field name="notesStmt" gloss="notes statement">collects together any notes providing information about a text additional to that recorded in other parts of the bibliographic description.</field>
<field name="num" gloss="number">contains a number, written in any form.</field>
<field name="number" gloss="">indicates grammatical number associated with a form, as given in a dictionary.</field>
<field name="numeric" gloss="numeric value">represents the value part of a feature-value specification which contains a numeric value or range.</field>
<field name="nym" gloss="canonical name">contains the definition for a canonical name or name component of any kind.</field>
<field name="object" gloss="">contains a description of a single identifiable physical object.</field>
<field name="objectDesc" gloss="">contains a description of the physical components making up the object which is being described.</field>
<field name="objectIdentifier" gloss="object identifier">groups one or more identifiers or pieces of locating information concerning a single object.</field>
<field name="objectName" gloss="name of an object">contains a proper noun or noun phrase used to refer to an object.</field>
<field name="objectType" gloss="">contains a word or phrase describing the type of object being referred to.</field>
<field name="occupation" gloss="">contains an informal description of a person's trade, profession or occupation.</field>
<field name="offset" gloss="">marks that part of a relative temporal or spatial expression which indicates the direction of the offset between the two place names, dates, or times involved in the expression.</field>
<field name="opener" gloss="">groups together dateline, byline, salutation, and similar phrases appearing as a preliminary group at the start of a division, especially of a letter.</field>
<field name="oRef" gloss="orthographic-form reference">in a dictionary example, indicates a reference to the orthographic form(s) of the headword.</field>
<field name="org" gloss="organization">provides information about an identifiable organization such as a business, a tribe, or any other grouping of people.</field>
<field name="orgName" gloss="organization name">contains an organizational name.</field>
<field name="orig" gloss="original form">contains a reading which is marked as following the original, rather than being normalized or corrected.</field>
<field name="origDate" gloss="origin date">contains any form of date, used to identify the date of origin for a manuscript, manuscript part, or other object.</field>
<field name="origin" gloss="">contains any descriptive or other information concerning the origin of a manuscript, manuscript part, or other object.</field>
<field name="origPlace" gloss="origin place">contains any form of place name, used to identify the place of origin for a manuscript, manuscript part, or other object.</field>
<field name="orth" gloss="orthographic form">gives the orthographic form of a dictionary headword.</field>
<field name="outputRendition" gloss=""> describes the rendering or appearance intended for all occurrences of an element in a specified context for a specified type of output.</field>
<field name="p" gloss="paragraph">marks paragraphs in prose.</field>
<field name="param" gloss="">provides a parameter for a model behaviour by supplying its name and an XPath expression identifying the location of its content.</field>
<field name="paramList" gloss="">list of parameter specifications</field>
<field name="paramSpec" gloss="">supplies specification for one parameter of a model behaviour</field>
<field name="particDesc" gloss="participation description">describes the identifiable speakers, voices, or other participants in any kind of text or other persons named or otherwise referred to in a text, edition, or metadata.</field>
<field name="path" gloss="">defines any line passing through two or more points within a <gi>surface</gi> element.</field>
<field name="pause" gloss="">marks a pause either between or within utterances.</field>
<field name="pb" gloss="page beginning">marks the beginning of a new page in a paginated document.</field>
<field name="pc" gloss="punctuation character">contains a character or string of characters regarded as constituting a single punctuation mark.</field>
<field name="per" gloss="person">contains an indication of the grammatical person (1st, 2nd, 3rd, etc.) associated with a given inflected form in a dictionary.</field>
<field name="performance" gloss="">contains a section of front or back matter describing how a dramatic piece is to be performed in general or how it was performed on some specific occasion.</field>
<field name="persName" gloss="personal name">contains a proper noun or proper-noun phrase referring to a person, possibly including one or more of the person's forenames, surnames, honorifics, added names, etc.</field>
<field name="person" gloss="">provides information about an identifiable individual, for example a participant in a language interaction, or a person referred to in a historical source.</field>
<field name="persona" gloss="">provides information about one of the personalities identified for a given individual, where an individual has multiple personalities.</field>
<field name="personGrp" gloss="personal group">describes a group of individuals treated as a single person for analytic purposes.</field>
<field name="phr" gloss="phrase">represents a grammatical phrase.</field>
<field name="physDesc" gloss="physical description">contains a full physical description of a manuscript, manuscript part, or other object optionally subdivided using more specialized elements from the <ident type="class">model.physDescPart</ident> class.</field>
<field name="place" gloss="">contains data about a geographic location</field>
<field name="placeName" gloss="">contains an absolute or relative place name.</field>
<field name="population" gloss="">contains information about the population of a place.</field>
<field name="pos" gloss="part of speech">indicates the part of speech assigned to a dictionary headword such as noun, verb, or adjective.</field>
<field name="postBox" gloss="postal box or post office box">contains a number or other identifier for some postal delivery point other than a street address.</field>
<field name="postCode" gloss="postal code">contains a numerical or alphanumeric code used as part of a postal address to simplify sorting or delivery of mail.</field>
<field name="postscript" gloss="">contains a postscript, e.g. to a letter.</field>
<field name="precision" gloss="">indicates the numerical accuracy or precision associated with some aspect of the text markup.</field>
<field name="pRef" gloss="pronunciation reference">in a dictionary example, indicates a reference to the pronunciation(s) of the headword.</field>
<field name="prefixDef" gloss="prefix definition">defines a prefixing scheme used in <ident type="datatype">data.pointer</ident> values, showing how abbreviated URIs using the scheme may be expanded into full URIs.</field>
<field name="preparedness" gloss="">describes the extent to which a text may be regarded as prepared or spontaneous.</field>
<field name="principal" gloss="principal researcher">supplies the name of the principal researcher responsible for the creation of an electronic text.</field>
<field name="profileDesc" gloss="text-profile description">provides a detailed description of non-bibliographic aspects of a text, specifically the languages and sublanguages used, the situation in which it was produced, the participants and their setting.</field>
<field name="projectDesc" gloss="project description">describes in detail the aim or purpose for which an electronic file was encoded, together with any other relevant information concerning the process by which it was assembled or collected.</field>
<field name="prologue" gloss="">contains the prologue to a drama, typically spoken by an actor out of character, possibly in association with a particular performance or venue.</field>
<field name="pron" gloss="pronunciation">contains the pronunciation(s) of the word.</field>
<field name="provenance" gloss="">contains any descriptive or other information concerning a single identifiable episode during the history of a manuscript, manuscript part, or other object after its creation but before its acquisition.</field>
<field name="ptr" gloss="pointer">defines a pointer to another location.</field>
<field name="publicationStmt" gloss="publication statement">groups information concerning the publication or distribution of an electronic or other text.</field>
<field name="publisher" gloss="">provides the name of the organization responsible for the publication or distribution of a bibliographic item.</field>
<field name="pubPlace" gloss="publication place">contains the name of the place where a bibliographic item was published.</field>
<field name="punctuation" gloss="">specifies editorial practice adopted with respect to punctuation marks in the original.</field>
<field name="purpose" gloss="">characterizes a single purpose or communicative function of the text.</field>
<field name="q" gloss="quoted">contains material which is distinguished from the surrounding text using quotation marks or a similar method, for any one of a variety of reasons including, but not limited to: direct speech or thought, technical terms or jargon, authorial distance, quotations from elsewhere, and passages that are mentioned but not used.</field>
<field name="quotation" gloss="quotation marks">specifies editorial practice adopted with respect to quotation marks in the original.</field>
<field name="quote" gloss="quotation">contains a phrase or passage attributed by the narrator or author to some agency external to the text.</field>
<field name="rdg" gloss="reading">contains a single reading within a textual variation.</field>
<field name="rdgGrp" gloss="reading group">within a textual variation, groups two or more readings perceived to have a genetic relationship or other affinity.</field>
<field name="re" gloss="related entry">contains a dictionary entry for a lexical item related to the headword, such as a compound phrase or derived form, embedded inside a larger entry.</field>
<field name="recordHist" gloss="recorded history">provides information about the source and revision status of the parent manuscript or object description itself.</field>
<field name="recording" gloss="recording event">provides details of an audio or video recording event used as the source of a spoken text, either directly or from a public broadcast.</field>
<field name="recordingStmt" gloss="recording statement">describes a set of recordings used as the basis for transcription of a spoken text.</field>
<field name="redo" gloss="">indicates one or more cancelled interventions in a 		 document which have subsequently been 		 marked as reaffirmed or repeated.</field>
<field name="ref" gloss="reference">defines a reference to another location, possibly modified by additional text or comment.</field>
<field name="refsDecl" gloss="references declaration">specifies how canonical references are constructed for this text.</field>
<field name="refState" gloss="reference state">specifies one component of a canonical reference defined by the milestone method.</field>
<field name="reg" gloss="regularization">contains a reading which has been regularized or normalized in some sense.</field>
<field name="region" gloss="">contains the name of an administrative unit such as a state, province, or county, larger than a settlement, but smaller than a country.</field>
<field name="relatedItem" gloss="">contains or references some other bibliographic item which is related to the present one in some specified manner, for example as a constituent or alternative version of it.</field>
<field name="relation" gloss="relationship">describes any kind of relationship or linkage amongst a specified group of places, events, persons, objects or other items.</field>
<field name="remarks" gloss="">contains any commentary or discussion about the usage of an element, attribute, class, or entity not otherwise documented within the containing element.</field>
<field name="rendition" gloss="">supplies information about the rendition or appearance of one or more elements in the source text.</field>
<field name="repository" gloss="">contains the name of a repository within which manuscripts or other objects are stored, possibly forming part of an institution.</field>
<field name="residence" gloss="">describes a person's present or past places of residence.</field>
<field name="resp" gloss="responsibility">contains a phrase describing the nature of a person's intellectual responsibility, or an organization's role in the production or distribution of a work.</field>
<field name="respons" gloss="responsibility">identifies the individual(s) responsible for some aspect of the content or markup of particular element(s).</field>
<field name="respStmt" gloss="statement of responsibility">supplies a statement of responsibility for the intellectual content of a text, edition, recording, or series, where the specialized elements for authors, editors, etc. do not suffice or do not apply. May also be used to encode information about individuals or organizations which have played a role in the production or distribution of a bibliographic work.</field>
<field name="restore" gloss="">indicates restoration of text to an earlier state by cancellation of an editorial or authorial marking or instruction.</field>
<field name="retrace" gloss="">contains a sequence of writing which has been retraced, for example by over-inking, to clarify or fix it.</field>
<field name="revisionDesc" gloss="revision description">summarizes the revision history for a file.</field>
<field name="rhyme" gloss="">marks the rhyming part of a metrical line.</field>
<field name="role" gloss="">contains the name of a dramatic role, as given in a cast list.</field>
<field name="roleDesc" gloss="role description">describes a character's role in a drama.</field>
<field name="roleName" gloss="">contains a name component which indicates that the referent has a particular role or position in society, such as an official title or rank.</field>
<field name="root" gloss="root node">represents the root node of a tree.</field>
<field name="row" gloss="">contains one row of a table.</field>
<field name="rs" gloss="referencing string">contains a general purpose name or referring string.</field>
<field name="rubric" gloss="">contains the text of any <term>rubric</term> or heading attached to a particular manuscript item, that is, a string of words through which a manuscript or other object signals the beginning of a text division, often with an assertion as to its author and title, which is in some way set off from the text itself, typically in red ink, or by use of different size or type of script, or some other such visual device.</field>
<field name="s" gloss="s-unit">contains a sentence-like division of a text.</field>
<field name="said" gloss="speech or thought">indicates passages thought or spoken aloud, whether explicitly indicated in the source or not, whether directly or indirectly reported, whether by real people or fictional characters.</field>
<field name="salute" gloss="salutation">contains a salutation or greeting prefixed to a foreword, dedicatory epistle, or other division of a text, or the salutation in the closing of a letter, preface, etc.</field>
<field name="samplingDecl" gloss="sampling declaration">contains a prose description of the rationale and methods used in sampling texts in the creation of a corpus or collection.</field>
<field name="schemaRef" gloss="schema reference">describes or points to a related customization or schema file</field>
<field name="schemaSpec" gloss="schema specification">generates a TEI-conformant schema and documentation for it.</field>
<field name="scriptDesc" gloss="">contains a description of the scripts used in a manuscript or other object.</field>
<field name="scriptNote" gloss="">describes a particular script distinguished within the description of a manuscript or similar resource.</field>
<field name="scriptStmt" gloss="script statement">contains a citation giving details of the script used for a spoken text.</field>
<field name="seal" gloss="">contains a description of one seal or similar applied to the object described</field>
<field name="sealDesc" gloss="seal description">describes the seals or similar items related to the object described, either as a series of paragraphs or as a series of <gi>seal</gi> elements.</field>
<field name="secFol" gloss="second folio">marks the word or words taken from a fixed point in a codex (typically the beginning of the second leaf) in order to provide a unique identifier for it. </field>
<field name="secl" gloss="secluded text">Secluded. Marks text present in the source which the editor believes to be genuine but out of its original place (which is unknown).</field>
<field name="seg" gloss="arbitrary segment">represents any segmentation of text below the <soCalled>chunk</soCalled> level.</field>
<field name="segmentation" gloss="">describes the principles according to which the text has been segmented, for example into sentences, tone-units, graphemic strata, etc.</field>
<field name="sense" gloss="">groups together all information relating to one word sense in a dictionary entry, for example definitions, examples, and translation equivalents.</field>
<field name="sequence" gloss="">indicates that the constructs referenced by its children form a sequence</field>
<field name="series" gloss="series information">contains information about the series in which a book or other bibliographic item has appeared.</field>
<field name="seriesStmt" gloss="series statement">groups information about the series, if any, to which a publication belongs.</field>
<field name="set" gloss="setting">contains a description of the setting, time, locale, appearance, etc., of the action of a play, typically found in the front matter of a printed performance text (not a stage direction).</field>
<field name="setting" gloss="">describes one particular setting in which a language interaction takes place.</field>
<field name="settingDesc" gloss="setting description">describes the setting or settings within which a language interaction takes place, or other places otherwise referred to in a text, edition, or metadata.</field>
<field name="settlement" gloss="">contains the name of a settlement such as a city, town, or village identified as a single geo-political or administrative unit.</field>
<field name="sex" gloss="">specifies the sex of a person.</field>
<field name="shift" gloss="">marks the point at which some paralinguistic feature of a series of utterances by any one speaker changes.</field>
<field name="sic" gloss="Latin for &lt;mentioned&gt;thus&lt;/mentioned&gt; or &lt;mentioned&gt;so&lt;/mentioned&gt;">contains text reproduced although apparently incorrect or inaccurate.</field>
<field name="signatures" gloss="">contains discussion of the leaf or quire signatures found within a codex or similar object.</field>
<field name="signed" gloss="signature">contains the closing salutation, etc., appended to a foreword, dedicatory epistle, or other division of a text.</field>
<field name="soCalled" gloss="">contains a word or phrase for which the author or narrator indicates a disclaiming of responsibility, for example by the use of scare quotes or italics.</field>
<field name="socecStatus" gloss="socio-economic status">contains an informal description of a person's perceived social or economic status.</field>
<field name="sound" gloss="">describes a sound effect or musical sequence specified within a screen play or radio script.</field>
<field name="source" gloss="">describes the original source for the information contained with a manuscript or object description.</field>
<field name="sourceDesc" gloss="source description">describes the source from which an electronic text was derived or generated, typically a bibliographic description in the case of a digitized text, or a phrase such as "born digital" for a text which has no previous existence.</field>
<field name="sourceDoc" gloss=""> contains a transcription or other representation of a single source document potentially forming part of a <foreign>dossier gntique</foreign> or collection of sources.</field>
<field name="sp" gloss="speech">contains an individual speech in a performance text, or a passage presented as such in a prose or verse text.</field>
<field name="space" gloss="dimension">indicates the location of a significant space in the text.</field>
<field name="span" gloss="">associates an interpretative annotation directly with a span of text.</field>
<field name="spanGrp" gloss="span group">collects together span tags.</field>
<field name="speaker" gloss="">contains a specialized form of heading or label, giving the name of one or more speakers in a dramatic text or fragment.</field>
<field name="specDesc" gloss="specification description">indicates that a description of the specified element or class should be included at this point within a document.</field>
<field name="specGrp" gloss="specification group">contains any convenient grouping of specifications for use within the current module.</field>
<field name="specGrpRef" gloss="reference to a specification group">indicates that the declarations contained by the <gi>specGrp</gi> referenced should be inserted at this point.</field>
<field name="specList" gloss="specification list">marks where a list of descriptions is to be inserted into the prose documentation.</field>
<field name="spGrp" gloss="speech group">contains a group of speeches or songs in a performance text presented in a source as constituting a single unit or <soCalled>number</soCalled>.</field>
<field name="sponsor" gloss="">specifies the name of a sponsoring organization or institution.</field>
<field name="stage" gloss="stage direction">contains any kind of stage direction within a dramatic text or fragment.</field>
<field name="stamp" gloss="">contains a word or phrase describing a stamp or similar device.</field>
<field name="state" gloss="">contains a description of some status or quality attributed to a person, place, or organization often at some specific time or for a specific date range.</field>
<field name="stdVals" gloss="standard values">specifies the format used when standardized date or number values are supplied.</field>
<field name="street" gloss="">contains a full street address including any name or number identifying a building as well as the name of the street or route on which it is located.</field>
<field name="stress" gloss="">contains the stress pattern for a dictionary headword, if given separately.</field>
<field name="string" gloss="string value">represents the value part of a feature-value specification which contains a string.</field>
<field name="styleDefDecl" gloss="style definition language declaration">specifies the name of the formal language in which style or renditional information is supplied elsewhere in the document. The specific version of the scheme may also be supplied.</field>
<field name="subc" gloss="subcategorization">contains subcategorization information (transitive/intransitive, countable/non-countable, etc.)</field>
<field name="subst" gloss="substitution">groups one or more deletions with one or more additions when the combination is to be regarded as a single intervention in the text.</field>
<field name="substJoin" gloss="substitution join">identifies a series of possibly fragmented additions, deletions or other revisions on a manuscript that combine to make up a single intervention in the text</field>
<field name="summary" gloss="">contains an overview of the available information concerning some aspect of an item or object (for example, its intellectual content, history, layout, typography etc.) as a complement or alternative to the more detailed information carried by more specific elements.</field>
<field name="superEntry" gloss="">groups a sequence of entries within any kind of lexical resource, such as a dictionary or lexicon which function as a single unit, for example a set of homographs.</field>
<field name="supplied" gloss="">signifies text supplied by the transcriber or editor for any reason; for example because the original cannot be read due to physical damage, or because of an obvious omission by the author or scribe.</field>
<field name="support" gloss="">contains a description of the materials etc. which make up the physical support for the written part of a manuscript or other object.</field>
<field name="supportDesc" gloss="support description">groups elements describing the physical support for the written part of a manuscript or other object.</field>
<field name="surface" gloss="">defines a written surface as a two-dimensional coordinate space, optionally grouping one or more graphic representations of that space, zones of interest within that space, and transcriptions of the writing within them.</field>
<field name="surfaceGrp" gloss="">defines any kind of useful grouping of written surfaces, for example the recto and verso of a single leaf, which the encoder wishes to treat as a single unit.</field>
<field name="surname" gloss="">contains a family (inherited) name, as opposed to a given, baptismal, or nick name.</field>
<field name="surplus" gloss="">marks text present in the source which the editor believes to be superfluous or redundant.</field>
<field name="surrogates" gloss="">contains information about any representations of the manuscript or other object being described which may exist in the holding institution or elsewhere.</field>
<field name="syll" gloss="syllabification">contains the syllabification of the headword.</field>
<field name="symbol" gloss="symbolic value">represents the value part of a feature-value specification which contains one of a finite list of symbols.</field>
<field name="table" gloss="columns">contains text displayed in tabular form, in rows and columns.</field>
<field name="tag" gloss="text encoding initiative">contains text of a complete start- or end-tag, possibly including attribute specifications, but excluding the opening and closing markup delimiter characters.</field>
<field name="tagsDecl" gloss="tagging declaration">provides detailed information about the tagging applied to a document.</field>
<field name="tagUsage" gloss="generic identifier">documents the usage of a specific element within a specified document.</field>
<field name="taxonomy" gloss="">defines a typology either implicitly, by means of a bibliographic citation, or explicitly by a structured taxonomy.</field>
<field name="tech" gloss="technical stage direction">describes a special-purpose stage direction that is not meant for the actors.</field>
<field name="TEI" gloss="TEI document">contains a single TEI-conformant document, combining a single TEI header with one or more members of the <ident type="class">model.resourceLike</ident> class. Multiple <gi>TEI</gi> elements may be combined to form a <gi>teiCorpus</gi> element.</field>
<field name="teiCorpus" gloss="">contains the whole of a TEI encoded corpus, comprising a single corpus header and one or more <gi>TEI</gi> elements, each containing a single text header and a text.</field>
<field name="teidata.certainty" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values expressing a degree of certainty.</field>
<field name="teidata.count" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values used for a non-negative integer value used as a count.</field>
<field name="teidata.duration.iso" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values available for representation of a duration in time using ISO 8601 standard formats</field>
<field name="teidata.duration.w3c" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values available for representation of a duration in time using W3C datatypes.</field>
<field name="teidata.enumerated" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values expressed as a single XML name taken from a list of documented possibilities.</field>
<field name="teidata.interval" gloss="">defines attribute values used to express an interval value.</field>
<field name="teidata.key" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values expressing a coded value by means of an arbitrary identifier, typically taken from a set of externally-defined possibilities.</field>
<field name="teidata.language" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values used to identify a particular combination of human language and writing system.</field>
<field name="teidata.name" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values expressed as an XML Name.</field>
<field name="teidata.namespace" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values used to indicate XML namespaces as defined by the W3C <ref target="http://www.w3.org/TR/1999/REC-xml-names-19990114/">Namespaces in XML</ref> Technical Recommendation.</field>
<field name="teidata.namespaceOrName" gloss="">defines attribute values which contain either an absolute namespace URI or a qualified XML name.</field>
<field name="teidata.nullOrName" gloss="">defines attribute values which contain either the null string or an XML name.</field>
<field name="teidata.numeric" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values used for numeric values.</field>
<field name="teidata.outputMeasurement" gloss="">defines a range of values for use in specifying the size of an object that is intended for display.</field>
<field name="teidata.pattern" gloss="regular expression pattern">defines attribute values which are expressed as a regular expression.</field>
<field name="teidata.point" gloss="">defines the data type used to express a point in cartesian space.</field>
<field name="teidata.pointer" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values used to provide a single URI, absolute or relative, pointing to some other resource, either within the current document or elsewhere.</field>
<field name="teidata.prefix" gloss="">defines a range of values that may function as a URI scheme name.</field>
<field name="teidata.probability" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values expressing a probability.</field>
<field name="teidata.probCert" gloss="">defines a range of attribute values which can be expressed either as a numeric probability or as a coded certainty value.</field>
<field name="teidata.replacement" gloss="">defines attribute values which contain a replacement template.</field>
<field name="teidata.sex" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values used to identify human or animal sex.</field>
<field name="teidata.temporal.iso" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values expressing a temporal expression such as a date, a time, or a combination of them, that conform to the international standard <title>Data elements and interchange formats  Information interchange  Representation of dates and times</title>.</field>
<field name="teidata.temporal.w3c" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values expressing a temporal expression such as a date, a time, or a combination of them, that conform to the W3C <title ref="#XSD2">XML Schema Part 2: Datatypes Second Edition</title> specification.</field>
<field name="teidata.text" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values used to express some kind of identifying string as a single sequence of unicode characters possibly including whitespace.</field>
<field name="teidata.truthValue" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values used to express a truth value.</field>
<field name="teidata.unboundedInt" gloss="">defines an attribute value which can be either any non-negative integer or the string "unbounded".</field>
<field name="teidata.version" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values which may be used to specify a TEI or Unicode version number.</field>
<field name="teidata.versionNumber" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values used for version numbers.</field>
<field name="teidata.word" gloss="">defines the range of attribute values expressed as a single word or token.</field>
<field name="teidata" gloss="">defines attribute values which contain an XML name.</field>
<field name="teidata.xpath" gloss="">defines attribute values which contain an XPath expression.</field>
<field name="teidata.xTruthValue" gloss="extended truth value">defines the range of attribute values used to express a truth value which may be unknown.</field>
<field name="teiHeader" gloss="TEI header">supplies descriptive and declarative metadata associated with a digital resource or set of resources.</field>
<field name="term" gloss="">contains a single-word, multi-word, or symbolic designation which is regarded as a technical term.</field>
<field name="terrain" gloss="">contains information about the physical terrain of a place.</field>
<field name="text" gloss="">contains a single text of any kind, whether unitary or composite, for example a poem or drama, a collection of essays, a novel, a dictionary, or a corpus sample.</field>
<field name="textClass" gloss="text classification">groups information which describes the nature or topic of a text in terms of a standard classification scheme, thesaurus, etc.</field>
<field name="textDesc" gloss="text description">provides a description of a text in terms of its situational parameters.</field>
<field name="textLang" gloss="text language">describes the languages and writing systems identified within the bibliographic work being described, rather than its description.</field>
<field name="textNode" gloss="">indicates the presence of a text node in a content model</field>
<field name="then" gloss="">separates the condition from the default in an <gi>if</gi>, or the antecedent and the consequent in a <gi>cond</gi> element.</field>
<field name="time" gloss="">contains a phrase defining a time of day in any format.</field>
<field name="timeline" gloss="days">provides a set of ordered points in time which can be linked to elements of a spoken text to create a temporal alignment of that text.</field>
<field name="title" gloss="analytic">contains a title for any kind of work.</field>
<field name="titlePage" gloss="title page">contains the title page of a text, appearing within the front or back matter.</field>
<field name="titlePart" gloss="subordinate">contains a subsection or division of the title of a work, as indicated on a title page.</field>
<field name="titleStmt" gloss="title statement">groups information about the title of a work and those responsible for its content.</field>
<field name="tns" gloss="tense">indicates the grammatical tense associated with a given inflected form in a dictionary.</field>
<field name="trailer" gloss="">contains a closing title or footer appearing at the end of a division of a text.</field>
<field name="trait" gloss="">contains a description of some status or quality attributed to a person, place, or organization typically, but not necessarily, independent of the volition or action of the holder and usually not at some specific time or for a specific date range.</field>
<field name="transcriptionDesc" gloss="">describes the set of transcription conventions used, particularly for spoken material.</field>
<field name="transpose" gloss=""> describes a single textual transposition as an ordered list of at least two pointers specifying the order in which the elements indicated should be re-combined.</field>
<field name="tree" gloss="ordered">encodes a tree, which is made up of a root, internal nodes, leaves, and arcs from root to leaves.</field>
<field name="triangle" gloss="">provides for an underspecified <gi>eTree</gi>, that is, an <gi>eTree</gi> with information left out.</field>
<field name="typeDesc" gloss="">contains a description of the typefaces or other aspects of the printing of an incunable or other printed source.</field>
<field name="typeNote" gloss="">describes a particular font or other significant typographic feature distinguished within the description of a printed resource.</field>
<field name="u" gloss="utterance">contains a stretch of speech usually preceded and followed by silence or by a change of speaker.</field>
<field name="unclear" gloss="">contains a word, phrase, or passage which cannot be transcribed with certainty because it is illegible or inaudible in the source.</field>
<field name="undo" gloss="">indicates one or more marked-up interventions in a document which have subsequently been marked for cancellation.</field>
<field name="unicodeName" gloss="unicode property name">contains the name of a registered Unicode normative or informative property.</field>
<field name="unit" gloss="">contains a symbol, a word or a phrase referring to a unit of measurement in any kind of formal or informal system.</field>
<field name="usg" gloss="usage">contains usage information in a dictionary entry.</field>
<field name="val" gloss="value">contains a single attribute value.</field>
<field name="valDesc" gloss="value description">specifies any semantic or syntactic constraint on the value that an attribute may take, additional to the information carried by the <gi>datatype</gi> element.</field>
<field name="valItem" gloss="">documents a single value in a predefined list of values.</field>
<field name="valList" gloss="value list">contains one or more <gi>valItem</gi> elements defining possible values.</field>
<field name="vAlt" gloss="value alternation">represents the value part of a feature-value specification which contains a set of values, only one of which can be valid.</field>
<field name="value" gloss="">contains a single value for some property, attribute, or other analysis.</field>
<field name="variantEncoding" gloss="">declares the method used to encode text-critical variants.</field>
<field name="vColl" gloss="collection of values">represents the value part of a feature-value specification which contains multiple values organized as a set, bag, or list.</field>
<field name="vDefault" gloss="value default">declares the default value to be supplied when a feature structure does not contain an instance of <gi>f</gi> for this name; if unconditional, it is specified as one (or, depending on the value of the <att>org</att> attribute of the enclosing <gi>fDecl</gi>) more <gi>fs</gi> elements or primitive values; if conditional, it is specified as one or more <gi>if</gi> elements; if no default is specified, or no condition matches, the value <val>none</val> is assumed.</field>
<field name="view" gloss="">describes the visual context of some part of a screen play in terms of what the spectator sees, generally independent of any dialogue.</field>
<field name="vLabel" gloss="value label">represents the value part of a feature-value specification which appears at more than one point in a feature structure.</field>
<field name="vMerge" gloss="merged collection of values">represents a feature value which is the result of merging together the feature values contained by its children, using the organization specified by the <att>org</att> attribute.</field>
<field name="vNot" gloss="value negation">represents a feature value which is the negation of its content.</field>
<field name="vocal" gloss="">marks any vocalized but not necessarily lexical phenomenon, for example voiced pauses, non-lexical backchannels, etc.</field>
<field name="vRange" gloss="value range">defines the range of allowed values for a feature, in the form of an <gi>fs</gi>, <gi>vAlt</gi>, or primitive value; for the value of an <gi>f</gi> to be valid, it must be subsumed by the specified range; if the <gi>f</gi> contains multiple values (as sanctioned by the <att>org</att> attribute), then each value must be subsumed by the <gi>vRange</gi>.</field>
<field name="w" gloss="word">represents a grammatical (not necessarily orthographic) word.</field>
<field name="watermark" gloss="">contains a word or phrase describing a watermark or similar device.</field>
<field name="when" gloss="days">indicates a point in time either relative to other elements in the same timeline tag, or absolutely.</field>
<field name="width" gloss="">contains a measurement measured along the axis parallel to the bottom of the written surface, i.e. perpendicular to the spine of a book or codex.</field>
<field name="wit" gloss="">contains a list of one or more sigla of witnesses attesting a given reading, in a textual variation.</field>
<field name="witDetail" gloss="witness detail">gives further information about a particular witness, or witnesses, to a particular reading.</field>
<field name="witEnd" gloss="fragmented witness end">indicates the end, or suspension, of the text of a fragmentary witness.</field>
<field name="witness" gloss="">contains either a description of a single witness referred to within the critical apparatus, or a list of witnesses which is to be referred to by a single sigil.</field>
<field name="witStart" gloss="fragmented witness start">indicates the beginning, or resumption, of the text of a fragmentary witness.</field>
<field name="writing" gloss="">contains a passage of written text revealed to participants in the course of a spoken text.</field>
<field name="xenoData" gloss="non-TEI metadata">provides a container element into which metadata in non-TEI formats may be placed.</field>
<field name="xr" gloss="cross-reference phrase">contains a phrase, sentence, or icon referring the reader to some other location in this or another text.</field>
<field name="zone" gloss="">defines any two-dimensional area within a <gi>surface</gi> element.</field>
</fields>
